Register of the Elizabeth Churchill Brown Papers 1943-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILES, 1837-1984
  - United States - Politics
    - General
      - Americanism (patriotism) (Folder 9)
        - General. Clippings, form letter, newsletters, notes, pamphlet, poem, press release, program, 1953-1975
        - Correspondence with Lt. Gen. George E. Stratemeyer, and others, 1954-1963
    - Elections, 1952-1980
      - Flyer and pamphlet, 1952. 1952 (Folder 10)
      - Newsletters and speech transcript, 1954. 1953-1954 (Folder 11)
      - Notes and newsletters, 1956. 1955-1958 (Folder 12)
      - Newsletter and correspondence with Herbert G. Klein and Maury M. Travis, 1960. 1959-1960 (Folder 13)
      - 1964
        - General. Clipping, newsletter, notes, 1963-1964 (Folder 14)
        - Goldwater campaign
          - General. Clipping, flyers, newsletter, notes, pamphlets, press releases, and mimeographed transcripts of speeches by Barry Goldwater, 1963-1964 (Folder 15)
          - Correspondence with Barry Goldwater, William Knowland, Republican National Committee, SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE/Goldwater, Barry M., 1964. (Folder 16)
      - 1968
        - General. Inaugural invitation and other miscellany, 1968-1969 (Folder 17)
        - McCarthy, Eugene. Clippings and notes, c. 1968 (Folder 18)
      - 1972
        - General. Campaign literature and miscellany, flyers, newsletters, SEE ALSO: Parties/Republican/Political activism/Conventions, 1971-1972. (Folder 19)
        - Ashbrook, John M. Campaign literature, 1972 (Folder 20)
        - McGovern, George. Biographical sketches, campaign literature, newsletters, pamphlets, and printed copy of Nathaniel Weyl, McGovern, The Candidate, 1971-1972 (Folder 21)
        - Muskie, Edmund. Campaign material, speech transcript with correspondence from Edmund Muskie, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Newsletter, 1980. 1979-1980 (Folder 2)
    - Organizations
      - Liberal
        - General. Correspondence with Lee Mortimer and the New Hampshire State Attorney General's office (Gall, Joseph F.), 1953-1956 (Folder 3)
        - American Committee on U.S. Soviet Relations. Newsletter, 1974
        - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA). Newsletters, a typescript and a mimeographed report on the ADA, notes, photocopy of newspaper clipping, typescript study, 1949-1961 (Folder 4-5)
        - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. Newsletter and pamphlet, 1947-1966 (Folder 6)
        - Asia Foundation. Pamphlets and reprint, 1954-1956
        - Atlantic Union Committee. Newsletter, 1956
        - Center for Inter-American Relations. Newsletter, 1972
        - Coalition on National Priorities and Military Policy. Newsletter, 1972
        - Contemporary Affairs Society. Form letter, n.d.
        - Council for a Livable World. Pamphlet, 1973
        - Fund for the Republic. Clipping, printed hearing transcript, newsletters, pamphlets, press release, radio broadcast transcript by Fulton Lewis, Jr., and a printed copy (pamphlet) of The American Right Wing, 1955-1966 (Folder 7)
        - Institute for American Democracy, Inc. Newsletter, 1966 (Folder 8)
        - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee. Newsletter, 1973
        - Rainbow. Pamphlet, n.d.
        - Washington Peace Center. Newsletter, 1966
      - Conservative
        - General. Flyers, newsletter, pamphlets, speech transcript, and a printed copy of Liberty and Property, First National Directory of "Rightist" Groups, Publications and Some Individuals in the United States, 3rd ed., 1957-1974 (Folder 9)
        - Alliance. Flyer, n.d. (Folder 10)
        - American Affiliates. Correspondence and speech transcript, 1956
        - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies. Correspondence, speech transcript, report, reprints, resolutions, SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE/Leetch, Madalen, 1957-1961.
        - American Legion. Correspondence, resolutions, statements, 1954-1962
        - American Public Relations Forum. Bulletin, 1954
        - American Youth for a Just Peace. Form letter and report, 1971
        - Angeles Associates (McClernan, Frank). Correspondence and mimeographed reports, How 'Facts Flow' Will Sell Conservatism, and A Public Relations Approach to Unified Conservative Action, 1961 (Folder 11)
        - Army and Navy Union, U.S.A. Form letter and newsletter, 1956
        - Campaign for the 48 States. Flyer, 1954
        - Citizens Councils. Correspondence, flyers, newsletters, notes, SEE ALSO: Communism/New Left/Black movements/Civil rights/Desegregation, 1957-1959. (Folder 12)
        - Congress of Freedom, Inc. Flyer, 1960
        - Conservative Book Club. Promotional material, c. 1968
        - Daughters of the American Revolution. Reprint and correspondence with Sara R. Jones and others, 1961-1964 (Folder 13)
        - Defenders of State Sovereignty and Individual Liberties. Flyer, newsletter, c. 1957 (Folder 14)
        - Edgewater Conference. Miscellany, n.d.
        - Florida States Righter. Newsletter, 1958
        - Foundation for Advanced Research Analysis. Newsletter, c. 1957
        - Freedom Leadership Foundation. Form letter and newsletter, 1972
        - Freedom School. Flyers, 1959
        - Independent American. Series of flyers, 1959
        - Institute for American Strategy. Copies of newspaper articles, form letters, 1972-1974 (Folder 15)
        - Intercollegiate Society of Individualists. Flyers, newsletter, 1960
        - John Birch Society. Transcript of speech by Robert Welch, SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE/Welch, Robert, 1960.
        - Liberty and Property, Inc. Miscellany, newsletters, progress reports, 1957-1958
        - Liberty Lobby. Correspondence, flyers, memoranda, newsletters, pamphlets, reports, testimony transcript, 1958-1968 (Folder 16-17)
        - Media Foundation. Flyer (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - Moral Rearmament Assembly. Newsletter, statement, 1959
        - National Economic Council, Inc. Form letter, newsletter, 1970-1971
        - National Education Program. Newsletter, speech transcript, 1956-1957
        - Non-Partisan League for Decency in Political Candidates. Correspondence, 1957
        - Oriel Society. Form letter and program, 1958
        - Public Action, Inc. Flyer, n.d. (Folder 2)
        - Right. Form letter, newsletters, 1957-1958
        - Student Committee for Congressional Autonomy. Correspondence, 1961
        - Texans for America. Newsletter, 1958
        - Threefold. Statement, 1957-1958
        - United States Day Committee, Inc. Pamphlet, n.d.
        - Virginia League. Newsletter, 1956
        - Virginians for Conservative Government. Correspondence, 1961
        - Voters U.S.A. Newsletter, 1956
        - Women Investors Research Institute, Inc. Memorandum, 1958
        - Young Americans for Freedom. Flyer, c. 1973
    - Political parties
      - General. Clipping, form letter, newsletter, press release, statements, and a printed copy of the Committee to Explore Political Realignment, Final Summary of Survey, 1951-1967 (Folder 3)
      - Democratic Party. Pamphlet, c. 1958 (Folder 4)
      - Republican Party
        - General
          - General. Copy of a newspaper editorial, notes, printed copies of Statement of Republican Principles and Objectives, and Herbert Hoover, The Constructive Character of the Republican Party, 1950-1954 (Folder 5)
          - Correspondence with Karl E. Mundt, the Republican National Committee, George Sokolsky, and others, 1951-1974 (Folder 6)
        - Clubs. Notes, pamphlets, speech transcripts, c. 1948-1954 (Folder 7)
        - Conventions. Campaign material, flyers, miscellany, newsletter, notes, pamphlets, 1952-1976 (Folder 8)
        - Publications. Newsletters and pamphlet, 1951-1957 (Folder 9)
    - Politicians. Biographical sketches, clippings, newsletters, reprints, 1951-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Venezuela. Clippings, serial issue (Carib), printed copies of the National Anti-Communist Movement of Free Venezuela, Proof of the Communist Domination of Venezuela, and Venezuela: A Powerful Communist Bulwark in America, and printed copy of the Dominican Press Society, Venezuela's "Democracy" Under Betancourt, 1958-1963 (Folder 11-12)
  - Vietnam
    - General (Folder 13)
      - General. Includes map, newsletter, notes, and printed copy of Vietnam Council on Foreign Relations, Introducing Vietnam, 1964-c. 1967
      - Correspondence with Dumitru Danielopol, Hilaire duBerrier, James D. Hittle (includes typescript study entitled The Changing Scene, Nguyen ton Hoan, William Loeb, Salipada K. Pendatun, Cecilia Steward (includes correspondence between Hilaire duBerrier and Leo Cherne, and others, 1965), 1957), 1955-c. 1970
    - Diem government (Folder 14)
      - General. Memoranda relating to the coup, newsletters, 1957-c. 1963
      - Dai Viet Nationalist Party (Nguyen ton Hoan, Secretary-General)
        - General. Declaration, 1957
        - Mimeographed bulletins, The Cause of Vietnam, c. 1958-1960
      - Religious problems. Letter, notes, and typescript reports of visit by U.N. Investigative Committee, 1957-1964
    - War
      - Non-printed material. Newsletters (issued by Strom Thurmond) outline, press releases, and statements by John F. Kennedy, Robert S. McNamara, Dean Rusk, and Lewis Walt, c. 1959-1972. (Folder 15-16)
      - Printed material. Newsletters, pamphlets, and printed copy of Nguyen Van Tuoi, South Vietnam and the National Liberation Front: An Assessment, 1954-1977 (Folder 17-18)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 19)
    - General, 1952-1971
      - General. Newsletters, notes, pamphlet, 1952-1971
      - Non-printed material. Mimeographed reports, Yugoslav Facts and Views, 1958
        - Kardelj, Edvard, On the Program of the League of Communists of Yugoslavia, (#51), 1958 May 9
        - Tito, Joseph Broz, The Tasks of the League of Communists in World Affairs and in the Development of Socialism in Yugoslavia, Part II (#52), 1958 May 19.
        - Tito, Joseph Broz, Yugoslavia Wants Good Relations Both with East and West, Excerpts from a speech by J.B. Tito (#67), 1958 Oct. 22.
    - Correspondence with the American Legion, John Foster Dulles, and Walter F. George, 1946-1956
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1950-1968
  - 68 postcards, primarily Europe and Middle East, undated (Envelope A)
  - 2 prints of Constantine Brown; 2 prints of Elizabeth Brown; 6 prints of the Korean War (one mounted); 1 print each of Generals Wallace M. Green, Payl L. Freeman, Jr. and Arthur G. Trudeau (mounted); 1 print of Adnan Menderes, circa 1958; 1 print anti Khrushchev display, 1959; 1 print of the Advisory Panel for "One Year Later" report prepared by the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, 1968; 2 prints and 2 negatives of Mr. and Mrs. Brown on their travels (South Korea, circa 1957?) (Envelope mB)
- DECLASSIFIED RECORDS, 1958 undated (Box-folder 41: 20)
  - 2011 June release of records, 1958 undated (Box-folder 41: 20)
    Report on the situation in Iran, undated; partial letter concerning proposed bill establishing a military intelligence service, undated; and partial letter to president of Korea regarding FY 1959 aid, 5 February 1958